Slide One
幻灯片一
First I would introduce myself briefly.
首先我做一个简单的自我介绍
I'm Zelun Chen from Netease and I'm a front-end and client development engineer.
我是来自网易的前端和客户端开发工程师陈泽伦
Today, the topic of my presentation is
今天我要讲的内容是
An Online Virtual Character Web Meeting With Expression Enhance Power By Machine Learning
一场基于机器学习加强表情表达的在线虚拟形象Web会议
where we use WebAssembly
我们使用了WebAssembly
to run Machine Learning Algorithm on the browser.
将机器学习算法运行在浏览器上
Now I'll give my presentation.
下面由我进行详细的演讲
Slide Two slide-2
幻灯片二
First, let me explain the background of our project.
首先来讲述一下我们这个课题的背景
Since the pandemic has caused great inconvenience for holding large conferences,
由于疫情期间开设一场大型的会议由许多不方便的地方
we are thinking about building a meeting scene within our game scene
所以我们就想能不能在我们的游戏场景中搭建一个会议场景
so that the lecturer and the audience can join the conference via virtual images
让演讲者和观众能够通过虚拟形象加入到会议中
and the online conference could be vivid and immersive.
举办一个接近现实的沉浸式线上会议
As is shown in this picture,
就如图中所示
this is our meeting scene that we have built.
这是我们的会议场景 目前已经实现
There are audience seats
台下有观众的座位
and there is a podium.
台上是演讲者的讲台
The lecturer can deliver a speech on the podium
演讲者可以在讲台上进行演讲
and display his or her presentation using the screen in the middle of it.
并通过讲台中间的幻灯片幕布进行展示
In the lower left corner is the virtual image of the lecturer.
左下角是演讲者的虚拟形象
So far, the faces of the audience and lecturers have been stiff
目前观众看周围观众和讲师的面部表情都是僵硬的
without rich facial expressions.
没有丰富的表情
That's not quite what we're looking for in our immersive experience
这就还没有达到我们沉浸式体验的目标
Now let me introduce our framework.
下面我先简单介绍一下我们的架构
Slide Three slide-3
幻灯片三
Our framework is as follows:
我们的架构是这样的
First, the audience and the lecturer go to the web page in their browser
首先观众和演讲者通过浏览器打开Web页面
and connect to a remote game client via WebRTC.
然后通过WebRTC连接远端的游戏客户端
Then their sounds can be transmitted through WebRTC from their local microphones to the game's audio module
之后可以通过本地的麦克风将声音通过WebRTC传递到游戏的声音模块
to allow lectures and Q&As.
实现演讲功能和答疑功能
After building the online meeting scene in this way,
当我们完成会议的这么一个线上场景后 就像上面所说的
we've been thinking that a successful meeting takes more than just these basic elements.
我们想到一场成功的会议不仅需要这些会议的基本要素
We also need to enhance interactions among attendees to create a vivid and immersive meeting,
还需要加强参会者之间的互动来打造一个更贴近真实世界的沉浸式会议
for example, to allow the audience to turn around and see the look on other people's faces,
比如观众可以转头看到别的观众脸上的表情
or to say hello to each other,
可以打招呼等
or even to see the face of the lecturer.
观众们看到讲师脸上的表情
After thinking for some time,
我们经过一段时间的思考就想到
it occurs to us that we can use the browser to capture faces from their cameras and transmit them to virtual images
我们可以 可能可以通过浏览器捕捉摄像头里的人脸转到虚拟人物模型上
so that everyone can see.
让大家看到
Our algorithm group happens to have a machine-learning-based library of emoji transmission,
正好我们算法组有一个基于机器学习的表情迁移的库
so we were wondering if we could run this library on our browser.
我们就想着能不能将这个库跑在浏览器上呢
Slide Four slide-4
幻灯片四
So here's how we're going to run this whole algorithmic engineering.
这里先介绍一下我们整个算法工程的运行流程
First we need to use camera to capture video
首先我们需要捕捉摄像头的内容 获取当前这一帧的画面
and send it to our algorithm to get model node parameters.
将它发送给我们的算法工程在工程里去计算得到模型的顶点参数
Then we render these node parameters onto this virtual image in browser
然后将这些顶点参数渲染在浏览器的的这个虚拟形象的模型上
and repeat this step so as to convert real-time facial data into a web model.
然后重复这整一个步骤 就实现了实时的将人脸数据转化为模型
After that, we were thinking about how we can run this engineering on the Web.
然后我们就想到 这个工程我们要跑到Web上应该怎么做呢
Slide Five slide-5
幻灯片五
As our machine learning algorithm is based on C++
由于我们的机器学习算法工程是基于C++实现的
and only uses Opencv library and a machine learning inference engine internally,
内部只依赖了Opencv库和一个机器学习推理框架
all we need to do is to run this C++ code on Web.
那么我们所需要做的就是将这个C++工程运行在Web上
So we came up with three solutions.
于是我们想了三个方案
The first one is to rewrite our source code with Javascript
第一个方案是将我们的C++工程代码重新用Javascript的代码去重写
referencing OpencvJs library and the machine learning Inference engine Js lib.
引用OpencvJs库和用JS写的机器学习推理框架的库
But this requires that we know both C++ and JS development
但是这个方案需要同时掌握C++开发和JS开发
and the essential difference between them,
并且需要需要知道两者实际上的差异
which is a lot of work.
这个的工作量是十分大的
So we didn't adopt this solution in the end.
所以我们最后没有选择这个方案
The second solution is to deploy algorithmic engineering on the server
第二个方案是将算法工程部署在服务器上
and to invoke it through back end Api interface.
通过服务器的接口进行调用
But since we need real-time facial data to build the model,
但是由于我们需要实时的将人脸数据转化为模型数据
there will be network request time latency,
这种方式会有网络请求的耗时
so we didn't adopt this solution, either.
所以我们也没有选择这个方案
The third solution is to compile the entire C++ library to WebAssembly
第三个方案是将整个C++库编译成WebAssembly
and directly run it on the browser.
将它直接跑在浏览器上
In this way, the problems of the first two solutions won't occur.
就没有上面那两个方案的那些问题
Eventually, we adopted the third solution.
最终我们选择了这第三个方案
Slide Six slide-6
幻灯片六
So here is a routine way of compiling C++ to WebAssembly
这就是一个常规的将C++库编译成WebAssembly的流程
as shown in the current page.
如图上这样所示
We pack it up as a WASM file and run it on our browser.
我们打包成WASM文件后将其运行在浏览器上
Here are the results we got.
这里我们先给大家展示一下我们的成果
The first is how it works on the browser.
首先是运行在浏览器上的效果
As you can see, it doesn't work very well on the browser.
大家可以看到 运行在浏览器上它的性能不是特别的好
It takes about two seconds to convert facial data into model data,
它大概需要两秒的时间将人脸数据转化为模型数据
so it looks a bit laggy.
所以看起来有点卡顿
Then let's take a look at what we did on Unity,
接下来看一下我们在Unity上的效果
which is what we expect to see.
这是我们所预期想要达到的效果
Slide Seven slide-7
幻灯片七
We can tell by comparing the two videos
通过上面两个视频的对比可以发现
that our engineering doesn't work very well on WebAssembly.
我们的工程跑在WebAssembly上性能不好
So here we raise a couple of questions about running WebAssembly on Web in our algorithmic engineering
我们在这里提出一些在整个算法工程中通过WebAssembly跑到Web上的过程中发现的一些问题
to discuss with you.
和大家探讨一下
First of all, as a front-end development engineer,
首先 作为前端开发工程师
when packing the entire C++ algorithm engineering,
我们打包这整个C++算法工程的过程中
you need to know a lot of knowledge of CMake, CLang, and Cross Compile, and these libraries' source code,
需要去了解CMake CLang 交叉编译和这些外部库的源码
because some of these methods from outside libraries cannot run on WebAssembly.
因为可能这些外部库的某些方法在WebAssembly上并不能跑
And here we have an idea
我们在这里提出一个想法
that maybe we can build an library environment like Npm
能不能构建一个类似于Npm的库环境
to version the LLVM-complied code library written by a developer
让开发者编译后的LLVM编的Code库进行一个版本管理
so that WebAssembly developers can use these libraries easily whether they have knowledge of C++ or not.
让无论懂不懂C++的WebAssembly开发者都能去简单地使用这些库
Second, since most of our inference libraries support OpenMp
第二个我们发现大部分的推理库都使用OpenMp
instead of PThread,
并没有使用PThread
we cannot use WebAssembly's multi threading to optimize.
那么我们就不能使用WebAssembly的多线程去进行优化
There are also biological differences to be dealt with.
除此之外 还有许多生态上的差异能否考虑去抹平
Third, we have encountered bad performance on matrix calculation,
第三个 我们在底层的矩阵计算时候发现它的性能十分的低下
and would love to hear if you have any suggestions to optimize it.
大家是否有一些这方面的方案供我们去优化
Fourth, our WASM file is a source code that can be acquired through reverse engineering and decompilation in browser,
第四个 我们的WASM文件跑在浏览器上 是可以通过逆向工程去反编译得到的源码结果
which lacks support on encrypt solution and does not guarantee the safety of our algorithmic engineering.
那样对我们的算法的工程的保护性不是特别的好
Do you have any possible solutions to this?
大家是否有一些可行性的方案
Those are the four problems that we're dealing with.
以上四点是我们所遇到的问题
We have come up with some solutions to improve its performance.
然后我们也进行了一些自己的尝试对性能上面的一些优化
For example, we first thought about using some efficient Javascript libraries
比如 我们想到去使用一些效率较高的Javascript的库
and use EM_JS to call Javascript via WebAssembly.
然后通过WebAssembly去通过EM_JS调用Javascript的方法
This is certainly not a good solution as it requires communication between WASM and JS files
当然这个方案并不是那么好 需要WASM和JS文件进行通信
and those that call this library all need to be modified.
并且需要修改所有调用该库的地方
Can we use Web common algorithm library to write some web development methods
能不能让Web经常使用的算法库写一些Web方法呢
that automatically call underlying ES_JM
当调用环境是WebAssembly的时候
when the environment is WebAssembly?
可以自动地去底层调用ES_JM方法
Second, we tried to use SIMD experimental features
第二点 我们也尝试使用了SIMD的实践性方案
on the latest browser.
在最新的浏览器上使用
However, it didn't meet our expectations.
但是没有达到我们预期的要求
First of all, the audience and the lecturer may not be using the most up-to-date browser.
首先是观众和演讲者浏览器未必是最新的
Second, it doesn't make much difference to our computational efficiency.
其次 它对于我们的运算效率也没有显著的提升
Slide Eight slide-8
幻灯片八
Do you have any suggestions or opinions?
大家是否对我们的问题有一些看法或者观点呢
Please feel free to tell us, thank you.
欢迎告诉我们 谢谢